Hi there. My name is Erika Delemarre and I work in Marine Protected Area Outreach and Education for California State Parks.
And I want to welcome you here, to the shorelines of Monterey Bay. We're here in Central California on the West Coast
of the United States of America, and this section of the North American Coastline is renowned for the diversity of coastal
and marine life that lives here. The abundance of food, as well as the variety of habitats available along the shorelines and
underwater attracts a wide variety of marine life including animals such as the Southern Sea Otter, Harbor Seal, Sea Lions,
and many species of whales, dolphins, fish, invertebrates — not to mention more than 300 species of birds.
Now where I'm standing right now, looking South you can see Point Lobos State Natural Reserve. That is the state park that
covers that peninsula there behind me. The water between the natural reserve and here, that is the Point Lobos State Marine Reserve,
or a marine protected area — it covers this whole area.  Now this marine protected area, or what we call an "MPA,"  protects the
abundant wildlife that's found here, but also a couple of unique habitats. One, a towering kelp forest and two, a deep submarine canyon
that plunges to more than 6,500 feet deep in the Pacific Ocean — it's pretty incredible.
My name is Kameron Strickland, a science diver at California State University, Monterey Bay. We're going to get in the water
just behind me at Monastery Beach. Our faculty and students are actively conducting research in the Point Lobos State Marine Reserve.
Thanks to our virtual reality camera, we're able to bring you along with us so that you can experience a dive.
Now, let me tell you how to use the experience.
First, find a flat area nearby. It might your floor or backyard.
Walk slowly through or around the area as you scan it. Then place the 3d map of Point Lobos on the scanned area
by tapping the dots that appear on your screen. You can scale and move the 3d map to as large or small as you want by pinching and dragging.
Points of interest will then appear on the map. Activate content walking or moving towards a point of interest and bumping your device into its pin head.
In accessibility mode, you can also activate points of interest by tapping pin heads on the screen with your finger.
Once you activate a point of interest, be sure to look up, down, and around while exploring the environment.
We're so excited to take you underwater with us.
We're going to go get suited up, and then we'll meet you down at the beach.